Finding Aid for Emil Lorch Papers 1891-2004
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Historic Michigan buildings, 5 linear feet
  - St. Clair County
    - Port Huron (Box 15)
      [15-52]
    - St. Clair (Box 15)
      [15-53]
    - Miscellaneous (Box 15)
      [15-54]
  - St. Joseph County
    - Sturgis (Box 15)
      [15-55]
    - Miscellaneous (Box 15)
      [15-56]
  - Shiawassee County (Box 15)
    [15-57]
  - Van Buren County: Paw Paw (Box 15)
    [15-58]
  - Washtenaw County
    - Ann Arbor
      - John Anderson House, 2301 Packard Rd. (Box 15)
        [15-59]
      - Ann Arbor Club, 338 Main St. (Box 15)
        [15-60]
      - Barrett House, Oxford Rd. near Hill St. (designed by Lorch) (Box 15)
        [15-61]
      - Beckley House 1425 Pontiac Trail (Box 15)
        [15-62]
      - Catherine Breed House, 317 E. Ann St. (Box 15)
        [15-63]
      - Christine Breed House 1020 W. Huron St. (Box 15)
        [15-64]
      - Churches (Box 15)
        [15-65]
      - Court House (1877) (Box 15)
        [15-66]
      - Court House (1956) (Box 15)
        [15-67]
      - DKE Chapel, 609 E. William St. (Box 15)
        [15-68]
      - Alex Dow House, Barton Hills (designed by Lorch)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 15)
          [15-69]
        - Correspondence (Box 15)
          [15-70]
        - Garage (Box 15)
          [15-71]
      - Eberbach School (Box 15)
        [15-72]
      - Frieze-Wilgus House 1547 Washtenaw Ave. (Box 15)
        [15-73]
      - Cornelius Goodrich House, 205 S. State St. (Box 15)
        [15-74]
      - Charles E. Green House, 415 E. William St. (Box 15)
        [15-75]
      - Louis P. Hall House, 3735 Tubbs Rd. (Box 15)
        [15-76]
      - H.H. Higbie House (Box 15)
        [15-77]
      - Hiscock House, 911 N. Main St. (Box 15)
        [15-78]
      - George Jackson House 1321 Forest Ct. (Box 15)
        [15-79]
      - Jail, 637 N. Main St. (Box 15)
        [15-80]
      - Lorch House 1023 Forest St
        - Notes and drawings (Box 15)
          [15-81]
        - Blueprints (Box 15)
          [15-82]
      - William S. Maynard House, 330 S. Main St. (Box 15)
        [15-83]
      - U.B. Phillips House, 1954 Cambridge St. (designed by Lorch) (Box 15)
        [15-84]
      - Post Office, N. Main at Ann St. (Box 15)
        [15-85]
      - Sudworth House, 712 E. Ann St. (Box 15)
        [15-86]
      - Thompson-Sinclair House, 1223 Pontiac Trail (moved to Greenfield Village) (Box 15)
        [15-87]
      - Ticknor-Campbell House, 2781 Packard Rd. (Box 15)
        [15-88]
      - Wilson-Wahr House, E. Ann at Division St. (Box 15)
        [15-89]
      - Clifford Woody House (designed by Lorch) (Box 16)
        [16-1]
      - S.J. Zowski House, Washtenaw and Austin Ave. (Box 16)
        [16-2]
      - Houses, Miscellaneous (Box 16)
        [16-3]
      - Miscellaneous (Box 16)
        [16-4]
      - General architectural histories (Box 16)
        [16-5]
      - University of Michigan
        - Angell Hall (Box 16)
          [16-6]
        - Engineering and Architecture Building (Box 16)
          [16-7 and 16-8]
        - Milles Fountain (Box 16)
          [16-9]
        - Old Museum Building (Box 16)
          [16-10]
        - President's House (Box 16)
          [16-11]
        - Union (Box 16)
          [16-12]
        - West Medical Building (Box 16)
          [16-13]
        - General (Box 16)
          [16-14 to 16-16]
    - Chelsea (Box 16)
      [16-17]
    - Dexter
      - Judge Dexter House
        - Miscellaneous (Box 16)
          [16-18 to 16-30]
        - Heating (Box 16)
          [16-31]
        - Furnishings (Box 16)
          [16-32]
        - Athletic field (Box 16)
          [16-33]
        - Financial reports (Box 16)
          [16-34 and 16-35]
        - Bank statements (Box 16)
          [16-36]
        - Correspondence relating to remodeling by University of Michigan (Box 16)
          [16-37]
        - Blueprints (Box 16)
          [16-38]
      - Field House (Box 16)
        [16-39]
      - Litchfield House (Box 16)
        [16-40]
      - Miscellaneous (Box 16)
        [16-41]
    - Dixboro (Box 16)
      [16-42]
    - Freedom Township (Box 16)
      [16-43]
    - Manchester (Box 16)
      [16-44]
    - Saline (Box 16)
      [16-45]
    - Scio Church Rd. (Box 16)
      [16-46]
    - Sharon Township (Box 16)
      [16-47]
    - Webster Township (Box 16)
      [16-48]
    - Superior Township (Box 16)
      [16-49]
    - Willow Run
      (Willow Run Airport filed in Wayne County)
      - Spencer Mansion House (Box 16)
        [16-50]
      - Notes (Box 16)
        [16-51]
    - York Township (Box 16)
      [16-52]
    - Ypsilanti
      - Cleary College (Old) (Box 16)
        [16-53]
      - Eastern Michigan Edison Company (designed by Lorch) (Box 16)
        [16-54]
      - General Motors (Detroit Transmission Division) (Box 16)
        [16-55]
      - Ladies Literary Club (Box 16)
        [16-56]
      - Quirk Theatre (Box 16)
        [16-57]
      - Miscellaneous (Box 16)
        [16-58 and 16-59]
    - Miscellaneous (Box 16)
      [16-60]
  - Wayne County
    - Belleville: Cozadd House (Box 17)
      [17-1]
    - Canton Township (Box 17)
      [17-2]
    - Dearborn
      - Miscellaneous (Box 17)
        [17-3]
      - Arsenal (Box 17)
        [17-4]
      - Fairlane (Box 17)
        [17-5]
      - Ford Plant (Box 17)
        [17-6]
      - Greenfield Village
        - Notes (Box 17)
          [17-7]
        - Plans and publications (Box 17)
          [17-8]
      - Haigh House (Box 17)
        [17-9]
      - Ross Residence
        - Plans (Box 17)
          [17-10]
        - Notes and correspondence (Box 17)
          [17-11]
    - Detroit
      - General (Box 17)
        [17-12 and 17-13]
      - Airport (Box 17)
        [17-14 and 17-15]
      - Callan House (Box 17)
        [17-16]
      - Churches, Miscellaneous (Box 17)
        [17-17]
      - City Hall (Old) (Box 17)
        [17-18]
      - Commercial buildings, Miscellaneous (Box 17)
        [17-19 and 17-20]
      - Fort Pontchartrain (Box 17)
        [17-21]
      - Fort Wayne
        - Correspondence (Box 17)
          [17-22]
        - Notes and plans (Box 17)
          [17-23]
      - Freer House (Merrill-Palmer School) (Box 17)
        [17-24]
      - Greusel House (Box 17)
        [17-25]
      - Frank A. Hecker House (Box 17)
        [17-27]
      - Houses, Miscellaneous (Box 17)
        [17-28]
      - J.L. Hudson Company (Box 17)
        [17-29]
      - Industrial buildings, Miscellaneous (Box 17)
        [17-30]
      - McColl House (designed by Lorch) (Box 17)
        [17-31]
      - James McMillan House (Detroit University Club) (Box 17)
        [17-32]
      - Mariners' Church (Box 17)
        [17-33]
      - Museum of Art (Old) (Box 17)
        [17-34]
      - National Bank Building (Box 17)
        [17-35]
      - Philo Parsons House (Box 17)
        [17-36]
      - Public and semi-public buildings, Miscellaneous (Box 17)
        [17-37]
      - Statler Hotel (Box 17)
        [17-38]
      - Wayne State University (Box 17)
        [17-40]
      - David Whitney Building (Box 17)
        [17-41]
      - Miscellaneous buildings (Box 17)
        [17-43 to 18-45]
    - Grosse Ile (Box 17)
      [17-46]
    - Grosse Pointe
      - Miscellaneous (Box 17)
        [17-47]
      - James Turner House (Box 17)
        [17-47a]
    - Plymouth (Box 17)
      [17-48]
    - Redford (Box 17)
      [17-49]
    - Trenton (Box 17)
      [17-50]
    - Willis (Box 17)
      [17-51]
    - Willow Run Air Terminal and Airport (Box 17)
      [17-52]
  - Wexford County: Cadillac (Box 17)
    [17-53]
- Photographs, 1 linear feet
  The Photographs series also collected for the Michigan Historic Buildings Survey consists of images of historic Michigan buildings and is arranged by name of county and then city. The photographs were either taken by Lorch or accumulated by him in the course of his work with the survey. This series includes multiple folders for Mackinac Island, Ann Arbor, and Detroit.
  - Album, work of George DeWitt Mason 1873-1931 (Box 17)
  - Album, Detroit Metropolitan Wayne County Airport (Box 17)
  - Alger County (Grand Island, Munising, West Munising, and Miscellaneous) (Box 18)
  - Allegan County (Allegan, Otsego, Plainwell, and Saugatuck) (Box 18)
  - Baraga County (Box 18)
  - Bay County (Bay City) (Box 18)
  - Berrien County (Benton Harbor, Berrien Springs, Buchanan, Coloma, Niles, St. Joseph, and Miscellaneous) (Box 18)
  - Calhoun County (Albion, Battle Creek, and Marshall) (Box 18)
  - Cass County (Cassopolis) (Box 18)
  - Charlevoix County (Charlevoix) (Box 18)
  - Cheboygan County (Mackinaw City) (Box 18)
  - Chippewa County (Sault Ste. Marie) (Box 18)
  - Clinton County (Maple Rapids) (Box 18)
  - Delta County (Fayette) (Box 18)
  - Emmet County (Harbor Springs and Petoskey) (Box 18)
  - Genesee County (Fenton, Flint, Goodrich) (Box 18)
  - Gogebic County (Sylvania) (Box 18)
  - Gratiot County (Ithaca) (Box 18)
  - Hillsdale County (Hillsdale, Jonesville, and Miscellaneous) (Box 18)
  - Houghton County (Houghton) (Box 18)
  - Huron County (Bad Axe, Grindstone City, and Port Hope) (Box 18)
  - Ingham County (East Lansing, Lansing, and Whitneyville) (Box 18)
  - Jackson County (Concord, Grass Lake, and Spring Arbor) (Box 18)
  - Kalamazoo County (Climax, Kalamazoo, and Miscellaneous) (Box 18)
  - Kent County (East Grand Rapids and Grand Rapids) (Box 18)
  - Keweenaw County (Fort Wilkins), 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Lapeer County (Lapeer) (Box 18)
  - Lenawee County (Blissfield, Cambridge Junction, Clinton, Irish Hills, Macon, Springville, Tecumseh, Tipton) (Box 18)
  - Livingston County (Brighton, Hartland, Rushton) (Box 18)
  - Mackinac County
    - Mackinac Island
      - Businesses (Box 18)
      - Dwellings
        - Beaumont House (Box 18)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 18)
      - Fort Mackinac (Box 18)
      - Street scenes (Box 18)
      - Views (Box 18)
        (see also UAm outsize folder)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 18)
    - St. Ignace (Box 18)
  - Macomb County (Mount Clemens, Utica, Washington, and Miscellaneous) (Box 18)
  - Manistee County (Manistee) (Box 18)
  - Marquette County (Marquette and Huron Mountain Club) (Box 18)
  - Mason County (Box 18)
  - Mecosta County (Paris) (Box 18)
  - Menominee County (Box 18)
  - Monroe County (Monroe and Miscellaneous) (Box 18)
  - Muskegon County (Muskegon) (Box 18)
  - Oakland County (Bloomfield Hills, Drayton Plains, Farmington, Pontiac, Royal Oak, South Lyon, Miscellaneous) (Box 18)
  - Ottawa County (Eastmanville, Holland, Lamont) (Box 18)
  - Presque Isle County (Presque Isle Lighthouse) (Box 18)
  - Saginaw County (Saginaw) (Box 18)
  - St. Clair County (Algonac, Port Huron, St. Clair) (Box 18)
  - St. Joseph County (Constantine, Mendon, White Pigeon) (Box 18)
  - Upper Peninsula, Unidentified (Box 18)
  - Van Buren County (Paw Paw) (Box 18)
  - Washtenaw County
    - Ann Arbor
      - Businesses
        - Broadway (Box 18)
        - Main St (Box 18)
        - State St.: James Foster Art Store (Box 18)
      - Dwellings
        - Ann St (Box 18)
        - Broadway (Box 18)
        - Dexter Rd (Box 18)
        - Division St (Box 18)
        - Forest St.: Lorch House (Box 18)
        - Huron St (Box 18)
        - Liberty St (Box 18)
        - Main St (Box 18)
        - Packard Rd (Box 18)
        - Pontiac Trail: Sinclair House (Box 18)
        - Warren Rd (Box 18)
        - Washtenaw Ave.: Wilgus House (Box 18)
      - University of Michigan buildings (Box 18)
        (includes drafting house of Engineering Building)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 18)
    - Chelsea (Box 18)
    - Dexter
      - Judge Dexter House (Box 18)
        (see also Uam outsize folder)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 18)
    - Dixboro (Box 18)
    - Manchester (Box 18)
    - Saline (Box 18)
    - Ypsilanti (Box 18)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 18)
  - Wayne County
    - Dearborn
      - Greenfield Village (Box 18)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 18)
    - Detroit
      - Businesses
        - D&C Warehouse (Box 18)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 18)
      - Churches (Box 18)
      - Dwellings
        - Brewster and Jefferies Projects (Box 18)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 18)
          (see also outsize folder, UAm)
      - Fort Pontchartrain (Box 18)
      - Fort Wayne (Box 18)
      - Parks (Box 18)
      - Public buildings (Box 18)
      - University of Detroit (Box 18)
      - Wayne State University (Box 18)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 18)
    - Grosse Ile (Box 18)
    - Grosse Pointe (Box 18)
    - Highland Park (Box 18)
  - Unidentified/miscellaneous (Box 18)
    (also see HABS banquet, 1934)
  - Painting, watercolor: "Twas a shack in the woods" (Box 18)
  - Portraits (Box 18)
- Architectural drawings
  The Architectural drawings series (13 outsized folders) is arranged alphabetically by state, county, and city. Like the Historic Michigan Buildings series and the Photographs series, Lorch accumulated multiple drawings for projects in which he was closely associated, notably the Mackinac Island restoration, the homes of Ann Arbor, and various Detroit restoration projects.
  - Connecticut: East Haddam, John Warner House (Folder 1)
  - New York: Hempstead, Raynor House, 336 Front St (Folder 1)
  - Wyoming
    - Moose: Mangus Log Cabin, Elbo Ranch (Folder 1)
      [see also outsize folder 12]
  - Michigan
    - Bay County: Bay City, Medor-Trombley House (Folder 1)
    - Calhoun County
      - Albion: Albion College (Folder 1)
      - Battle Creek: Van Der Meulen House (Folder 1)
    - Cheboygan County: Mackinaw City, Fort Michilimackinac (Folder 2)
    - Chippewa County: Sault Ste. Marie
      - Johnston House (Folder 3)
      - Schoolcraft House (Folder 3)
    - Ingham County: Lansing
      - O.M. Barnes House (Folder 3)
      - J.A. Kerr House (Folder 3)
    - Jackson County: Grass Lake, Soper House (Folder 3)
    - Lenawee County: Adrian, Charles M. Crosswell House (Folder 3)
    - Mackinac County: Mackinac Island
      - Maps of island and fort (Folder 4)
      - American Fur Company buildings (Folder 5)
      - Beaumont House (Folder 6)
      - Beaumont House (Folder 7)
        (continued)
      - Biddle House (Folder 6)
      - Biddle House (Folder 7)
      - Fort Mackinac
        - East Block House, no. 30 (Folder 8)
        - Guard House Building, no. 9 (Folder 8)
        - Old Hospital Building, no. 6 (Folder 8)
        - Wood Officers' Quarters, no. 8 (Folder 8)
        - Old Mission Church (Folder 8)
        - Unidentified plans (Folder 8)
      - Ann Arbor
        - Bennett House (Kempf House) (Folder 9)
        - Chapin House (Folder 9)
        - Hatch House (formerly on William, now 721 Division St.) (Folder 9)
        - Hiscock House, 911 N. Main St. (Folder 9)
        - Lorch House, 1023 Forest St (Folder 9)
        - Meuhlig House (Folder 9)
        - Schlanderer House, 504 S. Main St (Folder 9)
        - Sheriff's House (Jail), 637 N. Main St (Folder 9)
        - Sudworth House, 712 E. Ann St (Folder 9)
        - Thompson-Sinclair House 1223 Pontiac Trail (moved to Greenfield Village) (Folder 9)
        - Ticknor-Campbell House 2781 Packard Rd (Folder 9)
        - Detroit St. house (Folder 9)
        - Ann St. house (Folder 9)
        - 1116 Broadway (Folder 9)
        - 1127 Broadway (Folder 9)
        - 531 E. William St (Folder 9)
        - 1115 Woodlawn St (Folder 9)
      - Dexter: Judge Dexter House (Folder 10)
      - Ypsilanti: Conklin House (Folder 10)
    - Wayne County
      - Canton Township: Alfred Moore House (Folder 10)
      - Dearborn
        - Ross House (Folder 10)
        - Greenfield Village
          - Edison House (Folder 10)
          - Logan County Courthouse (Folder 10)
          - Plympton House (Folder 10)
      - Detroit
        - City Hall (Folder 11)
        - City Hall (Saarinen plan) (Folder 11)
        - Detroit and Cleveland Navigation Company Warehouse (Folder 11)
        - Fort Pontchartrain (Folder 11)
        - Memorial Hall (Saarinen Plan) (Folder 11)
        - Waterfront plan (Saarinen) (Folder 11)
  - Wyoming
    - Elk: Cunningham Homestead (Folder 12)
    - Moose: Main buildings A & B, Menor Ferry (Folder 12)
  - Michigan
    - Calhoun County: Albion, Albion College (Folder 12)
    - Kalamazoo County: Kalamazoo, Upjohn Company (Folder 12)
    - Mackinac County: Mackinac Island
      - Maps of island and fort (Folder 12)
      - Beaumont House (Folder 12)
      - Biddle House (Folder 12)
      - Fort Mackinac: Stone Officers' Quarters, no. 7 (Folder 12)
    - Livingston County: Hartland (Folder 12)
    - Washtenaw County
      - Ann Arbor
        - Ann Arbor Club, 338 Main St (Folder 12)
        - Architectural Building, University of Michigan (Folder 13)
        - Hiscock House (Folder 12)
        - Pontiac St. house (Folder 12)
        - President's House, University of Michigan (Folder 12)
      - Saline: Presbyterian Church (Folder 12)
    - Wayne County: Detroit
      - City Hall (Folder 12)
      - Fort Pontchartrain (Folder 12)
      - Fort Wayne (Folder 12)
Location of maps in the Lorch papers
CALHOUN COUNTY
Gymnasium for Albion College, Albion, Mich.: plot plan / H.K. Ferguson Company. -- 3-14-22. -- Blueprint. [In Outsize Folder 12]
EMMET COUNTY
Fort Michilimackinac, 1712-1782: exploration and excavation by Mackinac Island State Park Comm. / survey and plan by Dana P. Smith. -- 1932-1933. [In Folder 13-25]
Plan de Missilimakinak. -- [1717?]. -- Photostat. [In Outsize Folder 2]
Old Fort Michilimackinac about 1765-66: based on Lieut. Magra's map in General Gage papers, W.L. Clements Library / Raymond McCoy. -- [194-?]. -- Photostat. [In Outsize Folder 2]
[Plan of Fort Michilimackinac] / Magra. -- [17--]. -- Enlarged photostat. [In Outsize Folder 2]
[Plan of Fort Michilimackinac] / Nordberg. -- [17--]. -- Photostat. [In Outsize Folder 2]
[Plan of Fort Michilimackinac]. -- [17--]. -- Photostat. [In Outsize Folder 2]
Fort Michilimackinac, Mackinaw City State Park, Mackinaw City / surveyed by A.A. Ivey. -- Oct. 1956. -- Photostat. [In Outsize Folder 2]
KALAMAZOO COUNTY
Kalamazoo County historical map / prepared for the Kalamazoo Chamber of Commerce by A. A. Praus. -- [1952?]. [In Folder 13-60]
General layout, Portage Road development / the Upjohn Company. -- Nov. 1958. -- Blueprint. [In Outsize Folder 12]
LUCE COUNTY
Schematic map, Newberry State Hospital, Newberry Mich.: taken from aerial survey, May, 1942. -- [Lansing]: Michigan State Administrative Board, Buildings and Construction Division, [1942]. [In Folder 13-78]
MACKINAC COUNTY
Michillinimacnac. -- [1796]. -- Photostat. [In Outsize Folder 4]
Copy of a sketch made by Lieut. Ebenezer Massey, U.S. Army, in 1797 / copied by W.L. Rindge. -- Oc. 26, 1934. -- Sketch map. [In Folder 14-2]
[Map of Mackinac Island] -- [1797]. Photostat. [In Folder 15-13, and Outsize Folder 4]
[Survey of Mackinac Island]. -- [1805]. -- Photostat. [In Outsize Folder 4]
Plan of town & harbor of Michilimackinac / made by Aaron Greeley, deputy surveyor, in 1810; Rindge. -- Jan. 1947. -- Sketch map. [In Folder 14-2]
Plan of the Island of Michillimackinac, showing the military reservation upon that island / Aaron Greeley. -- August 1810. -- Photostat. [In Outsize Folder 4]
Map of the Island of Michilimackinac / C. Gratiot. -- [1816-1817]. -- Photostat. [In Outsize Folder 4]
[Enlargement of southeastern part of Michilimackinac I. ... surveys ... / by Mullett]. -- [1828]. -- Photostat. [In Outsize Folder 4]
Private claims at Michilimackinac / surveyed in Oct. & Nov. 1828 by John Mullet. -- [1828]. -- Photostat. [In Outsize Folder 4]
Private claims at Michilimackinac / surveyed in Oct. & Nov. 1828 by John Mullet. -- [194-?]. -- Sketch map. [In Folder 14-2]
General prospect of Fort Mackinaw County Michigan: for the commanding Capt. Scott / a drawing from W. Brenschuts. -- [184-]. -- Photostat. [In Outsize Folder 4]
Plan of the town and harbour of Michilimacinac / [Aaron Greeley]. -- July 13, 1848. -- Photostat. [In Outsize folder 4]
[Map of Mackinac Island / J.N. Macomb]. -- 1853. -- Photostat. [In Outsize Folder 4]
[Map of Mackinac Island / J.N. Macomb]. -- [1855-1856]. -- Photostat. [In Outsize Folder 4]
Map of the Mackinac National Park: showing the lots which it is proposed to lease and roads it is proposed to make: from a survey made under the direction of the Secretary of War / by G. Weitzel; H.A. Ulffers, assistant. -- 1875 -- Photostat. [In Outsize Folder 4]
American Fur Company buildings, plot plan / William P. Babcock, del. -- [193-]. -- Blueprint. [In Outsize Folder 5]
Old Fort Mackinac, Mackinac Island, Michigan / meas. & drn. W.L. Rindge. -- 22 Nov. 1934. -- Blueprint. [In Outsize Folder 4]
[Map of Mackinac Island / Morgan H. Wright]. -- [1937]. -- Photostat. [In Outsize Folder 4]
Site of Beaumont House: other historic buildings. -- [194-?]. -- Sketch map. [In Folder 15-13]
From HABS Mich. survey no. 215 plot plan / E.L. -- Feb. 1/47. -- Sketch map. [In Folder 14-2]
[Site map, buildings at corner of Market and Fort Streets, Mackinac Island] / A.A. Ivey. -- July 1952. -- Blueprint. [In Outsize Folder 12]
Plan of portion of town of Michilanimacinac: made from map of Aaron Greeley, deputy surveyor, in 1810, & compiled from his notes by Lucius Lyon, surveyor general, on July 15, 1848, with notations of present property lines taken from city assessor's map of 1938 / W.L. Rindge. -- Nov. 1, 1954. -- Blueprint. [In Outsize Folder 12]
WASHTENAW COUNTY
Residence of Judge Samuel W. Dexter, Dexter, Webster Township, Washtenaw County, Michigan: sketch map showing location, 1837-1937 / E.J. LaMothe, del., M.M. Conklin, del. -- 4-26-37. -- Photostat. [In Outsize Folder 10]
Eighth annual pilgrimage, June 1951, to Clinton, Tecumseh and Adrian / E. Lorch; Washtenaw Historical Society. 1951. -- Photostat. [In Outsize Folder 10]
WAYNE COUNTY
Fort Pontchartrain, 1701 A.D. -- [193-]. -- Blueprint. [In Outsize Folder 11]
Preliminary sketch showing proposed arrangement of buildings in Fort Pontchartrain: locations as shown by the plan of the French engineer in 1701. -- 9/21/35. -- Sketch map. [In Outsize Folder 11]
[Map of Fort Pontchartrain, Detroit] -- 1749. -- Photostat. [In Outsize Folder 11]
Fort Pontchartrain, Detroit, 1749 A.D.?. -- Mch. 3, 1935. -- Blueprint. [In Outsize Folder 11]
Fortifications Michigan, Fort Wayne Detroit River / drawn by M.C. Meigs. -- March 1849. -- Photostat. [In Outsize Folder 11]
Project for river front development in Detroit / Eliel Saarinen. -- 1924. -- Photostat. [In Outsize Folder 11]
Project for river front development in Detroit: memorial plaza / Eliel Saarinen. -- 1924. -- Photostat. [In Outsize Folder 11]
Project for river front development in Detroit: traffic system at memorial plaza / Eliel Saarinen. -- 1924. -- Photostat. [In Outsize Folder 11]
[Map of Detroit military tract] / L.D. Satterlee. -- 7/30 1941. -- Photostat. [In Folder 18-20]
General map of Fort Wayne, Detroit, Michigan / Office of the Post Engineer. -- Sep. 15, 46. -- Photostat. [In Outsize Folder 12]
Land acquisitions in Detroit Civic Center / City Plan Commission. -- March 27, 1952. -- Photostat. [In Folder 18-20]
Selective index of correspondents and subjects
Albion College
Correspondence and other materials, 1923-1925 and 1935, about the buildings at Albion College and overall plans for the campus
American Institute of Architects. Committee on Education.
Correspondence, reports, and other papers, 1913, November 1916, April 1917, and 1934-1935 of the Committee on Education of the AIA.
Angell, James Burrill, 1829-1916.
April 23 and August 1, 1906, Feb., July 29 and September 23, 1909; also correspondence, 1909, regarding the Angell memorial
Architectural League of America.
Reports, correspondence, minutes, etc. of the ALA. located in the correspondence series, 1901-1912; also in ALA series
Association of Collegiate Schools of Architecture.